Prescott, William Hickling, 1796-1859. William Hickling Prescott letters to Richard Bentley, 1837-1858 (MS Am 1218): Guide.
William Hickling Prescott letters to Richard Bentley,
1837-1858.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 1218
Prescott, William Hickling, 1796-1859.
1 box (.5 linear ft.)
Letters of American historian William Hickling Prescott to Richard Bentley.
44M-384. Purchased from Scribner; received: 1945.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material. Collection is open for research.
William Hickling Prescott, born in Salem, Massachusetts to a prominent family, wrote romantic and highly-regarded works of Spanish and Latin American history.
Arranged chronologically.
Letters to Richard Bentley, together with a few unidentified fragments of letters.
- Prescott, William Hickling, 1796-1859. 98 A. and Ms.LL.s. to Richard Bentley, 1794-1871.
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 5 May 1837., 1); 2 folders ([5]p.)
    Addressed on p.[8]
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 4 Oct 1837., 2); folder ([3]p.)
    addressed on p.[4]
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 20 Oct 1837., 3); folder ([2]p.)
    With addendum in another hand, p. [2-3] Addressed in another hand on p.[4]
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 9 Jan 1838., 4); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 28 Apr 1838., 5); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 24 Jul 1838., 6); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 30 Oct 1838., 7); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 8 Feb 1839., 8); 2 folders ([5]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 21 Feb 1839., 9); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 27 Mar 1839., 10); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 11 Jun 1839., 11); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Pepperell, 12 Oct 1839., 12); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 29 Jul 1840., 13); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 18 Aug 1840., 14); folder ([2]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 28 Feb 1841., 15); folder ([2]p.)
    With postscript in Prescott's hand.
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 30 May 1841., 16); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 10 Sep 1841., 17); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 15 Nov 1841., 18); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 18 Nov 1841., 19); folder ([2]p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 29 Apr 1842., 20); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 31 Dec 1842., 21); folder ([3]p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 1 Apr 1843., 22); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Pepperell, 14 Sep 1843., 23); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 30 Nov 1843., 24); folder ([2]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 30 May 1844., 25); folder ([4]p.)
    With postscripts in Prescott's hand.
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 30 Mar 1845., 26); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 30 May 1845., 27); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 15 Jul 1845., 28); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Pepperell, 14 Sep 1845., 29); folder ([3]p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 29 Nov 1845., 30); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 1 Apr 1847., 31); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 30 Apr 1847., 32); 2 folders ([8]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 13 May 1847., 33); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 30 Jun 1847., 34); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 30 Jul 1847., 35); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 11 Feb 1848., 36); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 5 Aug 1848., 37); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 9 Feb 1849., 38); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 30 Apr 1849., 39); 2 folders ([8]p.)
  - Ms.L.s;; Boston, 14 May 1849., 40); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 22 Oct 1849., 41); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 12 Nov 1849., 42); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 26 Nov [18]49., 43); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 4 Feb 1850., 44); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 4 Mar [18]50., 45); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Mivarts, 12 Sep 1850., 46); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 30 Sep 1850., 47); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 11 Dec [18]50., 48); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 13 Jan [18]51., 49); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 24 Mar [1851], 50); folder ([2]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 5 May [18]51., 51); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 20 May [18]51., 52); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 12 Jul [18]51., 53); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 19 Aug [18]51., 54); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 15 Dec [18]51., 55); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 22 Jan [18]52., 56); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 30 Jan [18]52., 57); 2 folders ([8]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 6 Jun [18]52., 58); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 20 Jul [18]52., 59); 2 folders ([8]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 11 Oct [18]52., 60); folder ([4]p.)
    With envelope.
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 26 Nov [18]52., 61); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 1 Feb [18]53., 62); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 22 Feb [18]53., 63); folder ([4]p.)
    With evnelope.
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 26 Apr [18]53., 64); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 28 Dec [18]53., 65); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 2 Jan [18]54., 66); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 16 May [18]54., 67); 2 folders ([8]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 20 Jun [18]54., 68); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 15 Aug 1854., 69); 4 folders ([15]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 19 Aug [18]54., 70); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 18 Oct [18]54., 71); 2 folders ([8]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 18 Oct 1854., 72); folder ([1]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 26 Nov [18]54., 73); folders ([8]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 5 Dec 1854., 74); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 13 Feb [18]55., 75); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 5 Mar [18]55., 76); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 29 May [18]55., 77); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 11 Aug [18]55., 78); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 9 Jul 1855., 79); 2 folders ([8]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 6 Nov [18]55., 80); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 12 Nov [18]55., 81); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 26 Nov [18]55., 82); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 10 Dec [18]55., 83); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 16 Dec [18]55., 84); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 18 Apr [18]56., 85); folder ([4]p.), and 3l.
    (1 written on both sides)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 4 Aug [18]56., 86); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 15 Sep [18]56., 87); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Pepperell, 27 Oct [18]56., 88); 1 1/2 folders ([6]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; [Boston?] 20 Dec [18]56., 89); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 25 Jan [18]57., 90); 1/2 folder ([2]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 9 Mar [18]57., 91); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Lynn [Mass.] 20 Jul [1857?], 92); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Lynn, Mass., 14 Sep [18]57., 93); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 18 Jan [18]58., 94); folder ([3]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 3 May 1858., 95); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 13 Aug [18]58., 96); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 20 Sep [18]58., 97); folder ([4]p.)
  - Ms.L.s.; Boston, 29 Oct [185-?], 98); 3 folders ([10]p.)
  - 7 unidentified pieces (5 fragments of letters, 2 envelopes), 99)